A Guide to the Correspondence and subject files of the Director of the Virginia Council on the Environment, 1970-1988
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Correspondence and subject files of the Director of the Virginia Council on the Environment, 1970-1988
The Library of Virginia
28672, 28975, 29657, 29900, 30902, 32359, 32687, 33128, 33747, 34993
143.5 cu. ft. (145 boxes)
Virginia Council on the Environment. Office of the Director.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Virginia Council on the Environment, Office of the Director,
Biographical Information
Recognizing the growing national concern over the condition of the environment, Governor A. Linwood Holton issued Executive Order Number 8 on September 16, 1970, establishing the Council on the Environment to advise him on ecological matters. An act passed by the General Assembly on April 10, 1972, created the council by statute.
The Council on the Environment was created to implement the environmental policy of the Commonwealth. This included advising the Governor and the General Assembly on environmental quality matters and the effectiveness of state programs; coordinating state communication with federal agencies; coordinating plans, programs and functions within the state; reviewing environmental impact statements of proposed state construction projects; preparing annual environmental quality reports; initiating and supervising programs to educate citizens on ecological matters; and initiating and supervising research programs.
As of 1992 the sixteen member council included five members appointed by the Governor, subject to confirmation by the General Assembly (includes the Chairman and the Administrator); the Chairmen of: the State Water Control Board, Game and Inland Fisheries Board, the Board of Conservation and Recreation, the Board of Historic Resources, Marine Resources Commission, the State Air Pollution Control Board, the Chesapeake Bay Local Assistance Board; and the Directors of the Dept. of Mines, Minerals, and Energy and the Dept. of Waste Management; the State Forester; and the Commissioners of Health, and Agriculture and Consumer Service.
The Council on the Environment was abolished by the creation of the Dept. of Environmental Quality on April 1, 1993, which consolidated the programs, functions and staff of the Council, the State Water Control Board, the Dept. of Air Pollution Control, and the Dept. of Waste Management.
Scope and Content
This series consists of the incoming and outgoing correspondence and memoranda of the director/administrator of the Council on the Environment; reports, project files, and subject files. This series documents administrative activities, establishment of policy and procedures, and major achievements of the agency.
The Reader's files consist of monthly memorandum, correspondence, impact statements, meeting agendas, and reports, assumably prepared for the Executive Director to read.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I: Correspondence and subject files, 1970-1974 [Accession 28692]
Series II: Correspondence and subject files, 1970-1975 [Accession 28975]
Series III: Correspondence and subject files, 1970-1977 [Accession 29657]
Series IV: Correspondence and subject files, 1974-1977 [Accession 29900]
Series V: Correspondence and subject files, 1971-1980 [Accession 30902]
Series VI: Correspondence and subject files, 1971-1979 [Accession 32359]
Series VII: Correspondence and subject files, 1967-1982 [Accession 32687]
Series VIII: Correspondence and subject files, 1975-1988 [Accession 33128]
Series IX: Correspondence and subject files, 1977-1986 [Accession 33747]
Series X: Correspondence and subject files, 1985-1991 [Accession 34993]
Contents List
- Series I: Correspondence and subject files [Accession 28692], 1966-1974., Extent: 6.75 cu. ft. (15 boxes). (Box 1-15)
  - Abandoned Autos I, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abandoned Autos II, 1967-1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Abatement in state owned facilities, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Air, Industry, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Air, Meteorological, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Aircraft emissions and fuel dumping, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Annual report funds info, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Billboards, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Budget financial records (Comprehensive health planning), 1969-1973 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Change on volume and Pollution of Discharge, 1968-1971 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Chesapeake Bay studies, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Chesterfield airport, 1969-1971 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Chickahominy River, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Chineoteague roundup, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Citizens suggestions for environmental improvement, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Citizen suits, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Combined systems, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Congressional testimonies, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Detergents, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Discarded vehicles, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Ecology and You - A collection of Ecology tips from the Denbigh Woman's Club, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Erosion and sedimentation, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Exhaust emissions from used automobiles, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Fairfax airport, 1970-1973 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Federal facilities (Air), 1971 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Flood hazard, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Flood plains, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Foreign efforts, 1970-1973 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Forest management practices, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Forest resources, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Forum original, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Forum speeches, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Forward to report, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Governor's Manpower Planning Council correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Highways - Kirby Roads, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Hunting and fishing, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Industrial pollution, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Industrial wastes, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Industry and power plants, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Intergovernmental Personnel Act, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Interstate Environment Compact Bill, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Junked autos, 1971-1974 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Litter, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Low lead gas, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Lube oils, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Luray town dump, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Marble Valley, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Memorandum, 1970 Oct.-1971 Dec. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Mined land law draft, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Minerals, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Mined land reclamation, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1974 Jan - Feb (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1974 March - June (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1974 July - Sept (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1974 Oct - Dec (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Mid-Atlantic Federal Regional Council conference, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Monitoring, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - National Governor's Conference, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - National Governor's Conference, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - National Governor's Conference Environmental Task Force, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Newport News Shipbuilding and Dry Dock Company, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Ocean Disposal, 1970-1971 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Ocean dumping, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Ocean dumping II, 1970-1972 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Oceanography, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Off road recreational vehicles, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Oil spills, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Oil spill clean up, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Parks and Virginia Outdoor plan, 1965-1968 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Position paper of Linwood Holton, candidate for Governor, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Personnel- Memos, notices, and correspondence, 1970-1973 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Pesticides, 1971-1972 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Power Plant Sitting Task Force, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Problem list, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Program Planning Task Force Administration, 1969-1972 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Project summaries, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Public relations, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Radiation, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Recreation, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Reports from Council Agencies, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Scenic rivers, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Scenic trails, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Seashore State Park, 1970-1971 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - SIRAS (Senior Institute for Research in the Arts and Sciences), 1971-1972 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Smith Mountain Lake, 1971-1972 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Snowmobiles, 1971-1972 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Soil, 1966-1970 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Soil and water conservation reports, 1970-1971 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Soil erosion and sediment control, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Southern Governor's Conference, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Southern Regional Environmental Conservation Council, 1970-1972 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - State facilities (Air), 1971 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Task Force on Hazardous Substances I, 1970-1972 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Task Force on Hazardous Substances II, 1970-1973 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Thermal pollution, 1969-1970 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Training operators (SWCB- State Water Control Board), 1969 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Transmittal of publications, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - UN Conference, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Vehicular traffic, 1971-1972 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - WCB (Water Control Board) Clippings, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Water resources agency, 1970-1971 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Water Resources Study Committee, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Weekly progress reports, 1971-1972 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Work program, 1970-1971 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Other states - Alaska, 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Other states - California, 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Other states - Colorado, 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Other states - Connecticut, 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Other states - Delaware, 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Other states - Florida, 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Other states - Georgia, 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Other states - Hawaii, 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Other states - Illinois, 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Other states - Indiana, 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Other states - Iowa, 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Other states - Maine, 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Other states - Maryland, 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Other states - Massachusetts, 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Other states - Maryland and Maryland Power Plants, 1971-1972 (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
  - Other states - Minnesota, 1971-1972 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Other states - Michigan, 1971-1972 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Other states - Mississippi, 1971-1972 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Other states - Montana, 1971-1972 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Other states - Nevada, 1971-1972 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Other states - New Mexico, 1971-1972 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Other states - New Jersey, 1971-1972 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Other states - New York, 1971-1972 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Other states - North Carolina, 1971-1972 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Other states - Ohio, 1971-1972 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Other states - Oklahoma, 1971-1972 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Other states - Oregon, 1971-1972 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Other states - Pennsylvania, 1971-1972 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Other states - Rhode Island, 1971-1972 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Other states - South Dakota, 1971-1972 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Other states - Utah, 1971-1972 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Other states - Vermont, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Other states - Vermont Environmental Center Inc., 1971 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Other states - West Virginia, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Other states - Washington, 1971-1972 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Other states - Wisconsin, 1969-1971 (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Series II: Correspondence and subject files [Accession 28975], 1970-1975., Extent: 6 cu. ft. (6 boxes). (Box 1-6)
  - United State Coast Guard, Public Notices, 1970 November - 1975 August (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Department of the Army, Corps of Engineers, Public Notices, Norfolk, 1972 January - 1973 December (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Department of the Army, Corps of Engineers, Public Notices, Miscellaneous, 1972 August - 1974 December (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Department of the Army, Corps of Engineers, Public Notices, Norfolk, 1974 January - December (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Department of the Army, Corps of Engineers, Public Notices, Norfolk, 1975 January - September (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Reader's file, Susan T. Wilburn, Environmental Impact Statement Coordinator, 1974 January (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Reader's file, Susan T. Wilburn, Environmental Impact Statement Coordinator, 1974 February (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Reader's file, Susan T. Wilburn, Environmental Impact Statement Coordinator, 1974 March (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Reader's file, Susan T. Wilburn, Environmental Impact Statement Coordinator, 1974 April (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Reader's file, Susan T. Wilburn, Environmental Impact Statement Coordinator, 1974 May (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Reader's file, Susan T. Wilburn, Environmental Impact Statement Coordinator, 1974 June (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Reader's file, Susan T. Wilburn, Environmental Impact Statement Coordinator, 1974 July (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Reader's file, Susan T. Wilburn, Environmental Impact Statement Coordinator, 1974 August (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Reader's file, Susan T. Wilburn, Environmental Impact Statement Coordinator, 1974 September (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Reader's file, Susan T. Wilburn, Environmental Impact Statement Coordinator, 1974 October (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Reader's file, Susan T. Wilburn, Environmental Impact Statement Coordinator, 1974 November (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Reader's file, Susan T. Wilburn, Environmental Impact Statement Coordinator, 1974 December (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Department of Highways and Transportation, Inter-Departmental Memorandum, 1972 August - 1973 October (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Department of Highways and Transportation, Inter-Departmental Memorandum, 1973 November - December (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Department of Highways and Transportation, Inter-Departmental Memorandum, 1974 January - March (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Department of Highways and Transportation, Inter-Departmental Memorandum, 1974 April (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Department of Highways and Transportation, Inter-Departmental Memorandum, 1974 May - July (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Department of Highways and Transportation, Inter-Departmental Memorandum, 1974 August - December (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Department of Highways and Transportation, Inter-Departmental Memorandum, 1975 January - September (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Barnes, Dennis, Correspondence, 1970-1973 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Barnes, Dennis, Correspondence, 1972-1975 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Experimental Environmental City, 1971-1974 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Flakne, Joseph T., 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Hanes, John W., Jr., 1970-1975 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Holton, Governor Linwood, 1971-1974 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Temple, T. Edward, 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Williams, Charles W., 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Council on the Environment Meeting, 1970 June (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Council on the Environment Meeting, 1970 September (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Council on the Environment Meeting, 1970 October (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Council on the Environment Meeting, 1970 November (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Council on the Environment Meeting, 1970 December (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Council on the Environment Meeting, 1971 February (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Council on the Environment Meeting, 1971 March (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Council on the Environment Meeting, 1971 May (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Council on the Environment Meeting, 1971 July (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Council on the Environment Meeting, 1971 July (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Council on the Environment Meeting, 1972 September (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Council on the Environment Meeting, 1972 December (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Budget request, 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Council of State Governments, 1970-1975 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - National policies on land use, 1971-1974 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Ilene Cohen, Land use Reader's file, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Land use dinner meeting, 1974 June (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Southeast Regional American Assembly on Land Use meeting (Key Biscayne, Florida), 1974 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Mason Neck Landfill and Subdivision Proposal (Fairfax County, Va.), 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Power plant siting, Correspondence, 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Power plant siting legislation, Correspondence, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Power plant siting legislation, Correspondence, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Power plant siting legislation, Correspondence, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Task Force on Environmental Management I, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Task Force on Environmental Management II, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Task Force on Environmental Management III, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Task Force on Environmental Management IV, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Task Force on Environmental Management V, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Task Force on Environmental Management, First draft report, 1973 August (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Task Force on Environmental Management, Final draft report, 1973 Fall (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Task Force on Environmental Management, Final report, 1973 October (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Task Force on Environmental Management, Reports and documents, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Environmental Goals Task Force, Membership and correspondence, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Environmental Goals Task Force, Organization of task force, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Environmental Goals Task Force, Working papers, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Environmental Goals Task Force, Correspondence, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Environmental Goals Task Force, Individual topic reports, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Environmental Goals Task Force, Text, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Environmental Goals Task Force, Draft, 1972-1974 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Environmental Goals Task Force, Public hearings, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Environmental Goals Task Force, Press clippings, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Outer Continental Shelf Office, Deepwater Port Study by ACOE, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Outer Continental Shelf Office, Proposal for office to Governor, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Outer Continental Shelf Office, Task Force Formulation and Advisory Board, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Outer Continental Shelf Office, Debbie Miles' Reader's file, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Outer Continental Shelf Office, Advisory Board meetings, 1974 July (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Outer Continental Shelf Office, Advisory Board meetings, 1974 August (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Outer Continental Shelf Office, Advisory Board meetings, 1974 August (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Outer Continental Shelf Office, Offshore drilling trip to Louisiana, 1974 August (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Citizens Against Pollution, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Council for Environmental Quality, Newsletters, 1971-1973 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Regional Council for Allegheny-Appalachian Commons, Electra M. McGay, 1972-1974 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Environmental Quality Form letters, A-C, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Environmental Quality Form letters, D-M, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Environmental Quality Form letters, N-W, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Newsletter, Environmental Education Report, 1972-1974 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Environmental Educators, Inc., undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - The Grantsmanship Center News, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Institute of Human Ecology, 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - University of Virginia newsletter, 1972-1975 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, 1971-1973 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Proposal to National Science Foundation, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Department of Defense, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Governor's National Council on Science and Technology, 1970-1972 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Governor's National Council on Science and Technology, 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Governor's National Council on Science and Technology, Meeting, 1973 October (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Governor's National Council on Science and Technology, Meeting, 1974 May (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - State Water Control Board, Blue Plains Treatment Plant (Washington, DC), 1971 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - State Water Control Board, Crow's Nest Harbour Project (Stafford County, Va.), 1972 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - State Water Control Board, Industrial Waste and Sewage, 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Reader's file, Gerald P. McCarthy, Executive Director, 1974 March (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Reader's file, Gerald P. McCarthy, Executive Director, 1974 April (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Reader's file, Gerald P. McCarthy, Executive Director, 1974 May (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Reader's file, Gerald P. McCarthy, Executive Director, 1974 June (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Reader's file, Gerald P. McCarthy, Executive Director, 1974 July (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Reader's file, Gerald P. McCarthy, Executive Director, 1974 July (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Reader's file, Gerald P. McCarthy, Executive Director, 1974 August (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Reader's file, Gerald P. McCarthy, Executive Director, 1974 September (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Reader's file, Gerald P. McCarthy, Executive Director, 1974 October (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Reader's file, Gerald P. McCarthy, Executive Director, 1974 November (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Reader's file, Gerald P. McCarthy, Executive Director, 1974 December (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Series III: Correspondence and subject files [Accession 29657], 1970-1977., Extent: 14.3 cu. ft. (39 boxes). (Box 1-39)
  - Council on the Environment Public Hearing, 1974 December (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Council on the Environment Public Hearing, 1976 October (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
  - VALC (Virginia Advisory Legislative Council), Environmental management, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - VALC (Virginia Advisory Legislative Council), Reorganization study, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - VALC (Virginia Advisory Legislative Council), Reorganization study, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - VALC (Virginia Advisory Legislative Council), Reorganizaton progress report, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
  - VALC (Virginia Advisory Legislative Council), Reorganization, 1971-1973 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
  - VALC (Virginia Advisory Legislative Council), Reorganization, 1971-1973 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - VALC (Virginia Advisory Legislative Council), Environmental Management Committee, Meetings, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - VALC (Virginia Advisory Legislative Council), Environmental Management Committee, Meetings, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - VALC (Virginia Advisory Legislative Council), Environmental Management Committee, Workshop, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - VALC (Virginia Advisory Legislative Council), Environmental Management Committee, Meetings, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Legislative correspondence, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - General legislation, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - House of Delegates correspondence, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Senate correspondence, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - General Assembly worksheets, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Legislative Study Committee, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Reports and Gunn's Committee, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Legislative correspondence, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - General legislation, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - General Assembly reports, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - General Assembly worksheets, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 11)